A Guide to the Papers from the Julian Bond Library, Nathaniel Rochester Community School, 1970-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers from the Julian Bond Library, Nathaniel Rochester Community School 1970-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
13347-a
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was given to the University of Virginia Library by Marjorie Towne, Rochester, New York, on March 9, 2006.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of Civil Rights activist, Georgia State Senator and Representative, and professor, Julian Bond (1940- ), chiefly consists of files of information about Bond collected by the Nathaniel Rochester Community School librarian Marjorie Towne, students, and other staff during his visits to the school, ca. 400 items (1 Hollinger box), 1970-2001.
Contents List
- Biographical Information about Julian Bond, 1970-1995 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Correspondence between Julian Bond and Nathaniel Rochester Community School, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Julian Bond Campaign Button, n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Local Coverage of Julian Bond's Visits to Rochester, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Materials prepared by staff at Nathaniel Rochester Community School to enrich the knowledge of students grades K-8, 1971-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- News Articles by Julian Bond, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 1:7)
- News Clippings about Julian Bond, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Packet of Articles about Julian Bond titled Julian Bond: Politics for the People,[post 1977] (Box-folder 1:9)
- Photographs of Julian Bond, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Publicity and Programs for other Rochester Appearances of Julian Bond, 1977-1995 (Box-folder 1:11)